Nilesh Patel

5 Avondale Close, Kingswinford, Dudley, West Midlands, DY6 7HJ
HOME 01384594477
MOBILE 07595253343
E-MAIL npatel_89@hotmail.com

PROFILE

I am a self motivated, hardworking and ambitious individual. My early medical experiences motivated me in fulfilling my training as an optometrist. I have gained an insight into the optician's world through hospital placements and working in high street practices. My previous employment at an independently own practice has granted me an insight in to the responsibilities of how to run a practice. It has also broadened my knowledge and understanding of the NHS and private sectors, the key roles and responsibilities an optician has in practice in both areas. I have a professional and conscientious work ethic and take pride in my accuracy and concern for detail. As well as being a good communicator and team player, I am able to work independently and take responsibility for making key decisions within my job, both relating to the patients and the practice.

.....

EDUCATION& QUALIFICATIONs

MCOptom

College of Optometrists - Qualified 2013

Services provided: MECS, Pre/Post cataract assessments, including SpaMedica.

BSc (Hons) Optometry

The University of Manchester - Graduated 2011

A-Levels: A - Biology, A - Chemistry, B - Maths

King Edwards VI College, Stourbridge. September 2005 - June 2007

GCSE: 4A*s, 4As, 2Bs including Maths, Science, English and IT

High Arcal School, Sedgley. September 2000 - July 2005

.....

SKILLS

Leadership and Teamwork

- Director of a small independent opticians.
- Confident and friendly communicator with external parties and patients.
- Comfortable in building team spirit and group relationships as a Level 2 cricket coach.
- University group and presentation work developed my ability to take a leading role.

.....

EXPERIENCES

Locum - February 2018 to Present

Currently practicing locum optometrist in the West Midlands.

John Biddle Opticians - March 2014 to January 2018

Joint venture partner/director of the Bridgnorth practice. I cover the other practices in Wellington and Madeley (Telford). I have developed competencies in cataract referral and post operative care, paediatric care and glaucoma referral refinement. Currently taken over by the Hakim Group.

Boots Opticians - Pre Registration July 2011 to April 2013

Worked in numerous branches, including Meadowhall Sheffield, Dollond & Aitchison Wakefield and Boots Opticians Chesterfield. Gained insight into management through Boots run courses and learnt of the roles and responsibilities for which an opticians practice requires to be successful.

Boots Opticians Meadowhall (Sheffield) - Summer School June 2010 to July 2010

Six week summer school at the Meadowhall branch undertook dispensing roles and also gained experience in delivering good customer care and service. Had to deliver a group based presentation on topics related to optometry.

OTHER

St Bartholomew and Royal London Hospital - October 2008

Voluntary two-week work experience placement. Shadowed a senior consultant plastic surgeon and experience surgical operations.

Roger Meredith Opticians - July 2007

Voluntary two-week placement at an independent practice.

INTERESTS

Qualified ECB Level 2 Cricket Coach

Coach children from ages 10 to 16 years of age and have supported county cricket coaches.

REFERENCES

Available on request